Tony Schwartz Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 2. Business and Professional Materials, 1940–2005, 54 linear feet
  - Client projects: commercial/for-profit work, 1958–2004, undated
    - Ultralife, 1991–1994
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1991-03-14–1994-03-09 (Box-folder 139/4)
      - Research materials, 1992-08–1994-04 (Box-folder 139/5)
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1994-03-16–1994-12-22 (Box-folder 139/6)
    - United Neighborhood Houses of New York, Inc. correspondence and research materials, 1991-05-06–1991-05-30 (Box-folder 139/7)
    - University of Illinois at Chicago scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1979-02-08–1987-05, (1 folder) (Box 139-140, Box 139, Box 140)
    - Upjohn Rogaine, 1987–1990
      - Scripts and correspondence, 1987-12–1990-01-25 (Box-folder 140/2)
      - Research materials and company reports, 1989-04 (Box-folder 140/3)
      - Scripts, 1988-11-15–1989-12-20 (Box-folder 140/4)
    - Us magazine material, 1979-10-11–1979-11-14 (Box-folder 140/5)
    - Video Base International material, 1983-08-1983–1984-03-15 (Box-folder 140/6)
    - Village Copier, Inc. scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1988-02-25–1988-03-29 (Box-folder 140/7)
    - Water Gap Realty script, 1992-02-26 (Box-folder 140/8)
    - WCBS Newsradio 88 scripts and notes, 1987-05-20–1987-07-02 (Box-folder 140/9)
    - Whirl vegetable shortening scripts and correspondence, 1959-04-29–1959-12-02 (Box-folder 140/10)
      Benton & Bowles, Inc.
    - The World Challenge scripts, 1981-06-15–1981-06-25 (Box-folder 140/11)
      For the book The World Challenge by Jean-Jacques Servan-Schreiber (New York: Simon and Schuster, 1981).
    - WQXR, 1974–1991
      See also Landco Labs, Inc. receipts, New Sounds, Inc., and Mobil WQXR scripts.
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1981-08-05–1991-01-04 (Box-folder 140/12)
      - Daily news logs, 1974-10–1975-03-28 (Box-folder 141/1)
    - Zabar's scripts and catalog, 1987–1988-07-18 (Box-folder 141/2)
    - Zenith, 1971–1995
      - Bose, 1994-03-25–1995-03-24 (Box-folder 141/3-4)
        Scripts and correspondence. Includes an American Federation of TV and Radio Artists HR report.
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1971-09-15–1989-04-03 (Box-folder 141/5)
        A letter in the file mentions Schwartz's book The Responsive Chord.
      - Teletext, 1983–1983-07-13 (Box-folder 141/6)
      - Advanced Video Imaging scripts and research materials, 1993–1994-02-04 (Box-folder 141/7)
  - Art and design work, 1999, undated
    Contains visual art comprised of graphics, dust jacket, brochure, and animations. Art work includes: Christmas Carol by Robert Gwathmey, unidentified pencil and paint sketch, a drawing by John Kaizer, and materials related to Karate Kids, an AIDS comic book for street children. Arranged in chronological order, then alphabetical by title.
    - Miscellaneous drawings and cartoon illustrations, undated, 1999-08-10 (Box-folder 142/1)
      John Kaizer, Robert Gwathmey, Karate Kids.
    - The Almost Making of the President 1968: A Narrative History of the Campaign That Almost Won book jacket, circa 1968 (Box-folder 142/2)
    - Children and God graphics, undated (Box-folder 142/3)
      See also Children and God in Series 3, Audiovisual publications.
    - Guerrilla Media graphics, circa 1967 (Box-folder 142/4)
    - Guerrilla Media graphic, "The Evening News," circa 1967 (Box-folder 220/9)
    - Pinocchio animation, undated (Box-folder 142/5)
    - Wexton Company brochure, undated (Box-folder 142/6)
  - Broadcast and recorded work, 1959–1999
    Contains files relating to theatrical sound design, film, sound recordings, and radio projects produced by Schwartz. Items include correspondence, playbills, reviews, liner notes, and promotional materials. Arranged in chronological order, then alphabetical by program/production title.
    - Miracle Worker playbill, 1959-10-19, undated (Box-folder 142/7)
      Photocopy of Playbill.
    - Playbill issue for Cool World and reviews, 1960-02-22–1960-02-23 (Box-folder 142/8)
    - One More River review, 1960-03-18 (Box-folder 142/9)
      Photocopied 1997-07-09.
    - You're Stepping on My Shadow reviews and Critics' Choice listing, circa 1962–1962-07-15 (Box-folder 142/10)
      New York Times and New York Herald-Tribune reviews appear to have been photocopied from microfilm negative.
    - Liner notes for Standing Here at the Present Time... A Sound Portrait of New York City, circa 1965–1965-10 (Box-folder 142/11)
      For a limited edition recording created for the Gallery of Modern Art photo exhibit marking the fiftieth anniversary of the Women's City Club of New York.
    - Sound of the Family of Man transcript and correspondence, 1967-07-18–1968-03-04 (Box-folder 142/12)
      In English and French.
    - WNYC press release, program guide, and other material, 1968-07-05–1995-01 (Box-folder 142/13)
      "WNYC Programs" bibliography, Adventures in Sound transcript submission (in English and French) for Prix Italia, Communication Journal public announcement transcript, letters from Seymour Siegel and Oscar Brand.
      See also recordings of Schwartz's WNYC radio programs in the Schwartz Collection; WNYC business correspondence; radio scripts and research items in Schwartz's public service clients material; and the WNYC subject file.
    - Frank Film film notes and article, circa 1973–1999-09-24 (Box-folder 142/14)
      New York State Writers Institute Classic Film Series (University at Albany, State University of New York).
    - All Things Considered letter of agreement, correspondence, and other material, 1975-09-22–1999-02-26 (Box-folder 142/15)
      Transcript, guest commentators schedule, promotional material for Lost and Found Sound — "Tony Schwartz: 30,000 Recordings Later," letters from Jim Russell.
    - Brochure for My Own Yard to Play In film screening, 1994-05-07 (Box-folder 142/16)
      Eighth Annual City Lore Festival of Film and Video.
    - New York Percussion Trio notes, undated (Box-folder 142/17)
  - Transcripts, 1956–1992
    Primarily transcripts of interviews and speaking engagements conducted by Schwartz. Materials include outline and notes of presentations, television transcripts, and correspondence. Arranged in chronological order, then alphabetical by title or radio station.
    Please note some transcripts might also be found in other series.
    - Art Directors Club presentation outline, 1956-03-06–1969-03 (Box-folder 142/18)
    - "General Presentation" outline, 1966 (Box-folder 142/19)
    - Advertising presentation outline, 1973-09 (Box-folder 142/20)
    - Environmental Media presentation outline, 1974-01 (Box-folder 142/21)
    - Anthony Bouza, Lawrence Lief interview and article, 1977-05-04–1983-11-13 (Box-folder 142/22)
      New York Times news clipping.
    - Federal-State Reports Conference materials, 1979-01-0 4 (Box-folder 142/23)
      Letter from Jacqueline Bailey, "Narrowcasting" notes.
    - Morning Edition correspondence and transcripts, 1982-04-13–1982-04-19 (Box-folder 142/24)
      Includes a letter from Debra Kirsch.
    - "Narrowcasting and Shame" presentation outline, 1987-03-10 (Box-folder 142/25)
    - Miscellaneous transcripts, circa 1989–1992-05-28 (Box-folder 142/26)
      Bill Moyers: The Public Mind, Face the Nation, Adam Smith's Money World, CBS Evening News with Dan Rather, Sound of Sight, "Type & Lettering," "What is a Trillion?," Bob Landers 1992-05-21, Marty Edleston 1992-05-28.
    - Media Minutes program scripts, 1990 (Box-folder 142/27)
      WQXR radio program.
    - Interview with Tony Schwartz script, 1991-04-19 (Box-folder 142/28)
      Deborah Feyerick.
    - Terry Shintani phone transcripts, 1992-04-30 (Box-folder 142/29)
      Conversations with Ray Brousseau, Dr. Terry Shintani.
    - CBS research director speech, undated (Box-folder 142/30)
      Handwritten at top of p. 1 of transcript: "Goldmark, CBS research director."
    - Currents: Media Salesmanship program transcript, undated (Box-folder 143/1)
      WNET television program.
    - "Generation Gap" transcribed notes, undated (Box-folder 143/2)
    - "Graphic Design" transcribed notes, undated (Box-folder 143/3)
    - New Dimensions in Sound reel contents, undated (Box-folder 143/4)
    - Recall and transcribed notes, undated (Box-folder 143/5)
    - Interview with Sandy Tredinnick, undated (Box-folder 143/6)
      Massachusetts universities presentation for Michael Rowan, "Mike Rowan and Kayla Schwartz re. Education."
    - "Tony and Jack" transcribed notes, undated (Box-folder 143/7)
    - "Six ad interview" notes, undated (Box-folder 143/8)
      Interview with Tony Schwartz.
      "Production 7501."
    - "Woodstock Interviews" transcribed notes, undated (Box-folder 143/9)
  - Teaching, 1955–2002
    Files contain correspondence, curricula, memoranda, course work, clippings, and other material relating to Schwartz activities as an instructor. Arranged alphabetically by institution name, then chronologically.
    - Center for Media in the Public Interest statement of purpose, correspondence, and other material, 1989-05-17–1997-08-18 (Box-folder 143/10)
      Promotional materials, articles, roster of participating organizations, course work, and a letter from John Doorley.
    - City University of New York (CUNY) anti-smoking initiative materials, circa 1986–1987-01-08 (Box-folder 143/11)
      Policy statements, student course work, promotional material, and transcript of anti-smoking hearing testimony.
      See also American Cancer Society.
    - City University of New York, Brooklyn College, Department of Television and Radio Journalism honors project correspondence and course work, 1992-06-25–1992-12-03 (Box-folder 143/12)
      TV/Radio 16, TV/Radio 26.8, letters from Sister Camille D'Arienzo.
    - Dalton School correspondence, course work, and other material, 1969-05–1991-11 (Box-folder 143/13)
      Drafts of The Dalton Experiment, media usage survey, curriculum proposal, news clippings.
    - Emerson College Division of Communication Studies, Health Communication Program correspondence, course work, and other material, 1993 August–1994-12-07 (Box-folder 143/14)
      Emerson Beacon; Boston Neighborhood Network/Emerson College viewer survey; material relating to CS 47l, Cable News Seminar, and CS 571, Media Strategies for the Health Professional courses; and letters from J. Gregory Payne and Philip Amato.
    - Folkways Records bulletin, circa 1955 (Box-folder 144/1)
      The Recording as a Teaching Tool: A Bulletin for Parents and Teachers.
    - Fordham University Center for Communications correspondence, project proposal, and other material, 1966-07-06–1968-08-06 (Box-folder 144/2)
      News clipping, Young Filmmakers program, photocopy of Shinichi Suzuki's Nurtured by Love, and letters from Rev. Louis Gates, Chaplain (Col.) Wallace Hale, Sister Margaret Flinton, Henry Putsch, Richard Coyne, and Rev. John Culkin.
    - Harvard University Center for Research and Development on Educational Differences materials, circa 1966 (Box-folder 144/3)
      A Chance to Grow [samples]. The World Across the Street (Harvard Graduate School of Education Association Bulletin).
    - Harvard University, School of Public Health, course and curriculum materials, 1985-2000
      See also Harvard University, School of Public Health, business correspondence.
      - Harvard University School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence, curriculum proposal, and other materials, 1985-04-09–1985-06-25 (Box-folder 144/4)
        List of handouts, Center for Health Communications concept paper, and letters from Jay Winsten and Harvey Fineberg.
      - Harvard University School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence and course material, 1986-11-20–1987-08-13 (Box-folder 144/5)
        Material relating to BEH 210c, Mass Communications and Public Health.
      - Harvard University, School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence, course work, and other materials, 1987-12-06–1988-07-07 (Box-folder 144/6)
        Material relating to BEH 210c, Mass Communications and Public Health, including a "Conference 2000" teleconference manual, notes from Harvard School of Public Health/New Sounds, Inc., and documents concerning the Massachusetts Saving Lives drunk driving campaign and the Smoking: New Findings, New Controversies program.
      - Harvard University School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence, course work, and other materials, circa 1989–1989-12-13 (Box-folder 145/1)
        Material relating to BEH 211c, Mass Communications and Public Health. Includes a Center for Health Communication special report, "Recommendations for Future Mass Media Campaigns to Prevent Preteen and Adolescent Substance Abuse," and the May-June 1989 issue of Harvard Magazine.
      - Harvard University School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior course work, 1990-02-09–1990-03-12 (Box-folder 145/2)
        Material relating to BEH 211c, Mass Communications and Public Health.
      - Harvard University School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence, course work, and other materials, 1991-01-14–1991-12-24 (Box-folder 145/3)
        Material relating to BEH 211c, Mass Communications and Public Health. Includes correspondence from William DeJong, materials from Diana Walsh, Guerrilla Media: Health Promotion's Electronic Arsenal excerpted interview, and "Increasing Organ Donation" background paper.
      - Harvard University School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence, course work, and other material, 1992-01-02–1992-07-27 (Box-folder 146/1)
        Material relating to HSB 211c, Mass Communications and Public Health, including letters from Barbara Moeykens, William DeJong, and Diana Walsh, and a Joseph Nelen obituary.
      - Harvard University, School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence, special reports, and other materials, 1992-09-21–1992-12-14 (Box-folder 146/2)
        Material relating to HSB 211c, Mass Communications and Public Health, including letters from William DeJong, news clippings, a Harvard School of Public Health photo directory.
      - Incomplete issue of USA Weekend, 1991-12-27 (Box-folder 220/10)
        Pages 3-18 of an issue of USA Weekend, probably used in HSB 211c, Mass Communications and Public Health, taught by Tony Schwartz in the Harvard University School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior.
      - Harvard University, School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence, course work, and other materials, 1993-01-06–1993-09-23 (Box-folder 146/3)
        Material relating to HSB 211cd, Developing Mass Media Communications. Includes photocopies of "Smoking and Your Health: Fenway Park's Mixed Message for Red Sox Fans," "Social Marketing for Public Health," and a Rowan and Michaels research survey.
      - Harvard University, School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior course work, 1994-01-13–1994-05-18 (Box-folder 146/4)
        Material relating to HSB 212cd.
      - Harvard University, School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence, 1995-01-24–1996-02-28 (Box-folder 146/5)
        A letter from William DeJong and correspondence between Tony Schwartz and Lisa Berkman.
      - Harvard University, School of Public Health, Department of Health and Social Behavior correspondence, 1997-10-20–2000-05-09 (Box-folder 146/6)
        Material relating to HSB 216e, Use of the Media to Work and Fight for Better Health Around the World. Includes letters from Lisa Berkman, email from Beth Townsend.
    - High School for Environmental Studies curriculum proposal, fliers, and other materials, undated, 1995-10-20 (Box-folder 147/1)
      File contains material relating to an environmental citizenship course, including a post card from Tony Wood (dated 1995-01-20); news clippings; miscellaneous papers; a transcript of a WINS public service announcement, "Investigating and Evaluating Environmental Issues and Actions: Skill Development"; and a note ("Money came from Schumann Foundation. John Moyers? To Council on Environment").
    - John Jay College of Criminal Justice correspondence, special reports, and other materials, 1975-10-07–1988-08-04 (Box-folder 147/2)
      Radio public service announcement transcripts and billing receipt; news clippings; memorabilia; "Is Crime Still a Problem?" full page advertisement; SPE 290, Techniques of Persuasion, final grade sheet; project proposal and research survey; Council of the City of New York Committee on Economic Development crime and arrest data; John Jay College Advisory Board roster; promotional material; and material relating to the Committee of Concerned Citizens Who Support John Jay College of Criminal Justice and the Institute for the Study of Media and Social Behavior.
      See also Concerned Students and Teachers of John Jay College, John Jay College of Criminal Justice in the PSA clients series, and the John Jay College subject file.
    - John Jay College of Criminal Justice program proposal, 1980-02-29–1983-03-10 (Box-folder 147/3)
      Proposal for Project SKILL: Skill in Language Through Law.
    - John Jay College of Criminal Justice, Police Cadet Program project proposal, special reports, and other materials, 1983–1990-08-14 (Box-folder 147/4)
      Dresner, Sykes and Associates educational interest survey; Captains Endowment Association news bulletin; Patrolmen's Benevolent Association questionnaire; "Career Planning: An Examination of Occupational Opportunities and Self-Achievement Skills"; Kern & Kochler minutes; NYPD sergeant exam grant proposal; NYPD sergeant exam prep course materials, including a handbill and public service announcement; 6th Annual Police Training Conference certificate of appreciation and other materials; and a soft body armor questionnaire.
    - John Jay College of Criminal Justice student strike correspondence and other materials, 1989-05-05–1990-05-19 (Box-folder 147/5)
      "Student Coalition and College Administration Accord," news clippings, handbill.
    - University of Maryland Department of Speech and Dramatic Art correspondence, 1974-11-07–1977-01-24 (Box-folder 148/1)
      Letters from Kathleen Jamieson.
    - Media Peace Corp correspondence and promotional materials, 1983-07-26–1991-07-08 (Box-folder 148/2)
    - New York Institute of Technology School of Media and Arts correspondence and syllabus, 1989-05-05, undated (Box-folder 148/3)
      Material relating to CA 0618, Topics in Communication and Media, and CA 0580, Vocabulary of the Media Critic. Includes letters from Bob Schuessler.
    - New York Public School 191, "Learning to Listen" photo layout, [circa late 1950s–early 1960s?] (Box-folder 229/10)
      Two sheets, each 14 1/2 by 10 inches, pasted to an illustration board, 15 1/4x20 inches. Each sheet contains images of children in a classroom; some images show Tony Schwartz at the front of the class with two tape recorders interacting with the children. A block of printed text with the heading "Learning to Listen" explains that the children are first and third graders in New York Public School 191 (Amsterdam School, Manhattan), who were photographed by Mal Wittman while listening to recordings of "the sounds of life around them." They also recorded and listened to their own voices.
    - New York University, Tisch School of the Arts, Interactive Telecommunications Program correspondence, course work, and other materials, circa 1981–2000-06-01 (Box-folder 148/4)
      Material relating to H79.2015.01, New Media and Interpersonal Behavior. Included are letters from George Agudow and Red Burns.
    - Pratt Institute, Graduate Design Program curriculum proposal and correspondence, 1965-04–1995-05-31 (Box-folder 148/5)
      Master/apprenticeship program.
    - Princeton University, Department of Politics, Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs correspondence, 1974-04-22–1983-04-19 (Box-folder 148/6)
      Letters from Stanley Kelley, Jr.
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, teaching proposals, and other materials, 1967-11-21–2002-06-11 (Box-folder 148/7)
    - State University of New York, Albany, lecture promotional poster, undated (Box-folder 230/1)
      Five copies of a circular poster, diameter 19 inches, promoting lecture #2 in L.C. 24, at SUNY Albany. "A live phone and tape presentation of sounds by Tony Schwartz." Credit: Harry Prichett. Also in the folder is a 10x8 inch black and white, three-hole-punched photographic image of the poster.
    - United States Department of Education correspondence, 1982-12-06–1983-06-06 (Box-folder 148/8)
      Relates to the U.S. Presidential Scholars Program.
    - University of Rhode Island Department of Speech Communication correspondence, 1983-05-13–1983-07-05 (Box-folder 148/9)
      "Political Persuasion in Campaign '84," material relating to Speech 430, Political Communication.
  - Speaking and media appearances, 1957–2000
    Materials relating to public appearances made by Schwartz. Arranged in chronological order, then alphabetical by institution or topic.
    - New York High Fidelity Show correspondence, 1957-09-04 (Box-folder 149/1)
      Letter from Joe Dilts.
    - Gooseneck desk lamp labeled "Tony Schwartz, Advertising Age 9th Annual Creative Workshop," circa 1966 (Box 218)
      [Commemorative?] metal and plastic gooseneck desk lamp, with an approximately 1 3/4x7x3 3/4 inch base; overall height is approximately 14 1/2 inches. The lamp features two small heads and power switches, and a brown power cord. The label is etched onto a metal plate in the center of the lamp's base.
    - Sounds Around Us memorabilia, correspondence, and review, 1962-11-29–1963-07-25 (Box-folder 149/2)
    - Paul Pimsleur article and obituary, 1967-02–1976-06 (Box-folder 149/3)
      "A Memory Schedule" and "Paul Pimsleur's Memory Schedule."
    - Spencer memorial church program, 1967-03-19 (Box-folder 149/4)
      Schwartz sermon, Seen and Not Heard.
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, handbills, and other materials, 1967-10-05–1998-09-28 (Box-folder 149/5)
      Management Development Forum roster, AIGA/New York biography, and letters from the American Association of Political Consultants, Centre for Culture and Technology.
    - Presentation notes and outlines, circa 1967–1991-02-19 (Box-folder 149/6)
      Vision 67, Fordham Conference, New Dimensions in Sound, Project 86, England, Environmental Media, Art Teachers, End of Line, AAAA, Democratic Senatorial Committee, Clutter, Albany, Bob Squire, Mnemonic Speech, Media and God, Management Horizons, Ultra-Sonics, Narrowcasting, Public Issue Radio Spots, Upjohn, Police, Hill & Knowlton, Narrowcasting and Shame.
    - Radio Advertising Bureau correspondence, proceedings, and other materials, 1968-05-16–1968-10-16 (Box-folder 149/7)
      Radio Workshop 1968, letters from Miles David.
    - Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy correspondence and photographs, 1968-06-05–1970-05-08 (Box-folder 149/8)
    - David Frost Show correspondence and presentation outline, 1969-10-07–1969-11-03 (Box-folder 149/9)
    - "Political Presentation" supporting materials and transcript, 1972-10-30–1982-01 (Box-folder 149/10)
    - U.S. Senate Commerce Committee correspondence, presentation notes, and other materials, 1973-02-05–1973-02-28 (Box-folder 149/11)